To be honest, there's a tube strike.
It's raining.
I'm. I get it, I get it, but it's going to be a great day.
I think starting with this session, which is going to be really interesting.
This is Tammuz Dubnov.
He's the Founder and CTO of AutonomyAI.
Doing some really cool stuff over there, and we're going to hear a bit about it.
Anyone a horror movie fan in the room
know?
Kind of unlucky because this is about when PM start writing code
over to you to.
Okay.
Pleasure to be here.
That was the first time I got introduced
the horror story, so that was nice and refreshing.
All right.
We will be talking about PMs writing code.
But that's not the true essence of this.
The essence of this is organizations want to become AI-native.
How is this a part of it?
And specifically, how can we start measuring it as you try and push
your organization to be more AI-native and and make those adoptions that are needed.
So before we start the problems
that hopefully, hopefully not, but likely you'll have anybody here
have had with the CFO, CD, CEO about AI spendings.
No. Wow.
Okay.
I have this like AI weekly like every other day I would ask the same question.
Okay, good for you guys.
You're in a better place than I am.
Anybody here have PMs and designers opening PRs.
Cool. Okay. Solid.
That's a great idea.
That's a great speed.
Next question.
Anybody here? No.
Merging on those PRs.
Yeah.
You guys are opening are meaningful or crap for lack of a better word okay.
So that's going to be a part of the the focus today.
Everybody wants to be AI-native.
If you don't want to be AI-native I'm not sure where you're in this room.
If you don't know what AI-native is and just open up basically any news channel.
But when I ask people.
Okay, what does AI-native mean to you?
Nobody can define it, at least not to me.
Do you guys know what AI-native means?
No. Do you guys want a harness?
Means those are the big buzzwords.
When I ask, nobody knows.
Everybody wants to have a harness.
Everybody wants to be AI-native and ask them, what does that mean?
They count. Really answer.
But the answer or the semi answer I do get is well,
being AI-native, means that PMs and designers, and our QAs
more people open pull requests, and that's somewhat true.
But in my view that is the symptom.
That's not what being a I'd really, really means.
So I'll give you my definition.
For me, being AI-native means that the person that cares,
the person has the authority to make the decision, is also the person
who can do the work that basically AI collapses, the gap collapses.
They hand over you as a person that cares about X and organization
has the authority to decide about X in the organization
can actually do the work by having agents execute.
Why that is really impactful and why that actually speeds up
organization is because the bottleneck for a while now has not been.
How fast can I write code?
The bottleneck has been the handoff.
The hey, as I have an idea designer, please make a figma.
Okay, let's talk about it a week after.
Let's see if we're a line.
Hey, I have this spec that I'm happy with your developer.
Let's factor into your screen.
Get to it this sprint next spring whenever we can work it in.
Now, that idea has waited a spring or two, and now I get to actually see it.
And now I need to do the review.
And we're going to do pixel perfect iterations.
And we're going to notice that you got this wrong. Need to take it.
We're going to notice that I got this wrong in the ticket.
And we're going to start iterating and doing those those really long handover
processes that slow down the velocity and actually took it.
So even if people can write code really quickly,
it doesn't mean that the features go out to to users faster.
And what you get when you do move towards AI-native
is that the people who care, can execute with agents almost immediately,
can do those iterations on the spot, and then when they are happy with it,
they can send it off to a developer to review.
And you basically have coupled in design review, you've coupled in product review
all before the developer even hears a word of what the feature is supposed to be.
And that's what it means.
It means collapsing stuff that can be days and weeks to, frankly, minutes.
And what that means is that
individual level is that everybody gets an upgrade.
We have PMs that don't really care about specs, they care about features.
Well, now they can actually implement an experience of features and doing them
as we get.
Engineers maybe don't care about the UI, UX,
at least a lot of the engineers I know.
They care much more about the system.
They're factoring how the components are built,
how the dependencies are mapped out.
Now they can start working on those.
And we have the senior engineers that frankly, want to work in architecture
and solve bigger and hard problems.
And suddenly with
AI-native organizations, everybody can go and can focus on the stuff
where they really matter.
And frankly, that's the stuff that they really care about.
And you can see that the data is moving that way as well.
People are not hiring more workers to do more work.
They're hiring more people to make decisions.
And you can see that
the the rate of hiring product managers is going up much faster
than developers, than not going up, because as organizations become more
AI-native, as they move faster, the bottleneck is the decision makers.
And you want the people bring through the the designers, the people
like you make that decision that will impact the user.
Now, in the Rush
Native, some people are doing it wrong and it can be really, really expensive.
Everybody heard of Uber and what's going on there?
Okay.
So this came out just to I think 3 or 4 days ago.
Uber has increased the area spend since 2024 by six x.
Now that seeks X growth was completely used within four months.
They are out of AI budget for the rest of the year.
And we asked them what the impact is of training with like fully a need
that everybody get all the tokens you want.
That's like the upward CFO conversation that you guys have magically not had.
You will get an answer saying
AI costs are getting harder to justify, people are more and more tokens.
But me as a business leader, I'm
not seeing how there's a link to actually moving faster on features.
And that's the really, really big gap.
It's just throwing more LLM compute that's doesn't fix an organization.
You actually want to be AI-native and give the people who can decide
the ability to execute
Microsoft.
And a similar phenomenon, they gave everybody Claude Code.
And now they're taking it away.
Because just giving Claude Code to more
and more people in romanization is a wonderful way to burn money.
It is not the right way to speed up the work.
And now if we actually want to see like
what is all these token budget, where is this bending going to?
Somebody is not a deep dive managing over 2400 companies and how they use AI.
And you can see from any $100 that you spend on AI, only $18
actually goes to meaningful code
that actually gets shipped to users.
A lot of it goes to stuff that gets reworked bugs that AI also generated,
and you get this wonderful loop of spending more and more money in less
because of the alignment and basically how the model is trained.
And now it's not a sad story.
Some people are doing a great job.
Shopify is doing a great job in becoming more AI-native,
but the focus is not necessarily on developers.
It's not about giving them higher limits on Claude Code.
It's about empowering the rest of the organization.
And again,
the people that can decide in their domain the ability to execute in their domain.
So you'll see, here's how it went all in one of cursor licenses.
And when they actually measured the stuff
that gets shipped from those non-technical individuals,
how much of it is valuable, how much of it needs to be written?
They said that 50% just gets accepted.
It means that the quality is so high
that the work getting done by those non engineers, it can actually be merged as is
and doesn't go to the development has to go and patch it endlessly.
And you see even the VP of engineering like very clearly says
the fastest growing groups are not the engineers for everybody else
that deeply cares about organization and now can actually impact it.
So if we try and break down the wrong ways
and the right ways, I'll give you what I see as the wrong ways.
If you just give a bigger limits and more
spendings to the same developers on the same tasks,
you will get a bigger budget, but you will get developers
that aren't really interested in the task that you've given them.
Because the same as before, and my experience developers
to work on tasks that they're not interested in in
the agenda era, we'll just hand it off to an agent,
and they will let the agents check itself and notice
there's an issue and fix itself and notice there's another issue and do effectively
huge token consumption in a single session for a bucket engineer,
had they cared,
would have probably seen me like, oh no, no, you went their own direction,
go this way.
But the the disinterested engineers will just hand it off
and let the agent loop endlessly, because they don't really feel the tokens that
you will give another way to, to undersell
you will give PMs and designers
prototyping tools so they can prototype faster
and they can create potentially things faster.
But that doesn't solve the big bottleneck that we talked about the handover.
It just gets them to create a figure faster and wait for the devs for longer.
It's like the army saying
in the US, sorry, up and wait, there's going to hurt to wait.
And lastly, we've seen a lot of organizations
give Claude Code to everybody.
Now code in the name is the word code.
People that don't know how to really look at code
don't really know what to do with cloud code, and giving it to PMs and designers
is a great way for them to go to your desk every other day to say, hey,
help me set up environment for broke or for them to open plan
are thousands of lines and total nonsense and basically ways for them
to increase the PR fatigue that your dev team is already feel.
And now the right way to
do all this is actually take the tools that are tuned for that type of user.
So Claude Code is a wonderful tool. Whole developers.
There are tools for a mess. In designers.
We focus on one as well.
Tanya is a tool for those non-technical individuals.
You move the person who cares to be the person that does the work.
So pixel perfect work that you put in a developer
that doesn't really care about how it looks.
It's stuff that's going to eat your token budget,
need to sleep because they don't really care.
And lastly, you do not let go of your guards.
We talk to organizations that have made a big jump to be AI-native.
And then the we go top down.
So we talk to to executives and leaders and organizations,
and then on calls, they will find out new features
in front of clients that don't match their product.
Not not physically, not functionality.
But everybody moves so fast and tries to be native and runs forward
that all of your guards, the stuff that engineering principles
have put in place
over the years of experience, they suddenly, suddenly disappeared.
So it is really important to keep those in place.
That's their quality assurance.
That's the way to make sure that AI doesn't
run forward and break your product and take it in
a totally different direction than what you intended.
I'm not going to talk about it in this talk
because there's not enough time.
But personally, I've adopted a methodology in our organization that we call plan,
Merge Polish and how you can keep those cards in while also moving
quickly in terms of code velocity without getting conflicts left and right.
But the key here is
same tools, different play.
The focus is on getting the people who care, the tools to execute,
and all
that confidence,
and enabling those non-technical individuals to touch code base that can be
brownfield can be extremely complicated, extremely legacy.
That confidence comes from the harness.
So again for for the harness buzzword not always knows
the world has Shimoda defined it is basically a harness
means that you saw the agent making a mistake,
and you make it unfeasible for the agent to make the same mistake again.
You put in some sort of wall
to see that the next time that happened, the agent gets automatic feedback.
Hey, you did this wrong. Correct it.
And the important thing here is that the
the harness needs to adapt, the mistake is made and mistake is realized.
The harness things to adapt to prevent that mistake from happening again.
So it's not something that's supposed to be handheld.
It's something that's supposed to grow and evolve organically with more usage in
over time.
So I'll tell you some of our
principles, as we do a lot of harness engineering internally for our tool.
And everybody here works in an organization with a code base,
often in massive code base.
So you need to harness the agents to actually know what the code is.
You need to understand it. They need to onboard themselves.
They do not need to depend on a developer to tell them what to do.
They need to be able to communicate with the user.
You can't depend on a user to anchor
and say in this file and this span of lines, let's work on it.
You need to understand
the product level language and what that actually translates into code.
And they need to manage really long sessions and keep the context fresh.
They need to be able to check their own
work to get automatic feedback loops and higher quality.
With that,
we also need to know what good means and of course they need to improve it.
That's the key part of the harness.
So we personally put a lot of emphasis on all of this.
But in particular when working with non-technical individuals,
you need somebody to own the code and read the code that's on the agent.
You don't want to translate all those code constraints
to the product every single time you talk to them, you want to eat them.
Just know that inherently and factor it in.
And you want the agent to check us off constantly.
There's nothing worse than that overconfident agent.
And finally, you want to learn
not just from an individual session, but from all of your users in parallel
so that the growth is actually exponential and truly accumulative.
And we often get is that sounds amazing?
But I just enough
like my code is really difficult, setting it up is not actually going to work.
And the answer is, frankly, we've never not been able to make it work.
Everything is feasible.
You just have to to go about it the right way.
Since we're talking about non-technical individuals,
take care of much more about the user facing.
So maybe if you're super complicated, micro system
architecture back in is not feasible to set up for them every time.
Focus more in front than we can run setups
than are crazy monopole multi repo
with like sibling libraries to be compiled so the agent can actually see it.
And we've done with everything in terms of security
from like secrets to access private repositories and artifacts
that contain like the core libraries that you need to actually run.
So everything is feasible for the agents can manage everything.
Now, we've not seen a case that is not manageable,
but it is really important to say
that people that care can't do work,
that they're not really authorized to do.
So there is very much a line in the sand.
The line in the sand is engineers most definitely have their place,
but it's in making the judgment calls on the actual engineering
decisions and architecture decisions that the DB, the back end,
and having them focus again on stuff that they care about more.
Whereas the non-technical individuals can focus on the user facing changes
and whether that's tiny stuff like copy to layout to new features,
to getting new x ray.
And what that actually goes down to is they can do the user facing the UX work,
and you get your engineers to focus on what really matters of AP.
Now this line sounds really nice and potentially obvious.
It is not. Not so easy.
It is more than expected that you will fail.
The merge we're going for is not 100, and knowing the line between a task
that involves backend and doesn't fall back in, it's not not all that clear,
especially to somebody non-technical that really wants to to make an impact.
So I'll give you an example from us.
We had this BR and we closed it.
The designer here was a PM and it did a lot of work.
The PR end up being a little over 1000 lines and new feature.
They wanted to have like an images to very specific part of the site.
So somebody jumps through the versions, they can see
visually what the other versions were and the agents succeeded.
And when they did a product review,
it worked beautifully, exactly like they wanted it.
And as soon as it went to the developer,
developer said, oh, we're not going to merge this.
And that was because the the agent made everything server side and stored
the images there.
And basically the user came back the next day, images would be gone,
whereas the developer said, oh, we can't store this
until we have an internal discussion to decide
how we want to store the meta DB, or we're putting it in the bucket.
I don't even know the answer to this,
so there's no way we're going to go with what the agent decided for the PMO.
And again, that's healthy for us.
That just meant this conversation got sped up.
The developers comfortable it.
The next day the feature was in and I think the week after and
and what the developer did is they took this branch, took all the front
and all the UX and changed the backend so that settle.
But the expectations shouldn't be, hey, 100%,
if a PM opens a PR, go and be mad at the developers for not arching,
you want them to do that part.
So now the the thing that really matters
for any data scientists in the room is how how do you measure it?
I'll tell you how we do it across the hundreds of orgs
and thousands of PRs that get opened with us and weekly monthly basis.
So the first thing to track is, frankly, the count of the pull request.
How many are open by non-technical individuals and ideally
by by which individual.
So you know that every is actually getting a enabled and impactful.
We have seen places where some non-technical
and are more confident open PRs, some are more hesitant.
You want everybody to actually feel comfortable.
You can track that just by the count, but beyond it, you want to make sure
that you're not adding PR fatigue by opening noise and clutter.
And that's where the merging comes in from.
From our number is just so you're familiar in average
non-technical contributor and organization.
In a quarter of openness about 50 there emerging is about 74%.
Which means that one out of four they accidentally overstepped.
And that's okay. That's not PR fatigue.
That's totally fine, that it's a level where we still have
a lot of trust between the PRC open and the dev team that reviews them.
And lastly, you also want to measure how much extra work
you're adding, not just in terms of PR reviews.
Sometimes developers will need to do follow up work because the agent doesn't
know.
Maybe some future roadmap plans and factors that are intended or whatnot.
And they're how we do this.
We measure from PR that are open and merge.
How many get merged without any dev interfering,
without them pushing more commits to fix, change, adjust.
And again, for us that is 84%.
So 84% of the PR merge generated by non-technical individuals
simply get merged,
which is a way to make sure that you are not increasing the burden
on the dev team, not just from PR fatigue, but from a task perspective.
The moral of the story
the point of being native is actually democratizing authorship
so that the person that is accountable, the person that has the authority, is
the person can do the work
without being dependent on a bunch of other individuals in the org,
and hoping that they do their work, or waiting for them to do the work.
And again, that's where the velocity and the disconnect between spending more on AI
but not feeling faster feature treatment.
And that's where they got us from.
And frankly, all you need is an OS on your code base to to make this possible.
And we're happy to talk to you about how we do it.
But you do want something that is absolutely coupled
in your code base to enable all those non-technical individuals
without giving them technical nature or plot code and lots of code.
Look at and that's it. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
We will have about
five minutes for questions anyone likes to ask me.
Okay, I'll start over here.
If you could pass it down.
I the metrics.
Do you create your own tool to get those metrics.
Because you know you had the last one which is number of that has zero dev
touches. Right.
If you're creating parts, how do you actually know which ones are
being touched by engineering and have you automated that.
Do you use a off the shelf tool?
Oh, we look at it ourselves.
Our system looks at every PR with the author
is and frankly, the author shows up is like that in our logs.
But in it there's a trace of the the user that offered it.
And then we look at the commit history before it was merged.
So, you know, the last commit made by the AutonomyAI agent.
And then
you see if more people actually pushed stuff to it
that changed the code, not just like emerging or rebasing.
And so that's where you can track a pretty, pretty easily.
Yeah. I was.
Wondering if you.
Also see this moving the other way as well.
So you sort of like moving the PM's more to the right.
Do you have the engineers moving more into the PM UI feature space as well?
A so a few things.
It's interesting that both moving in both directions.
One is I'll talk a little bit
about our process with plan, which was talking about
yes, developers want to move fast.
As such, they don't want to wait for product decisions, UX decisions
they won't be able to.
Hey, I built this feature and it works, at least from my perspective.
Let me get it in.
And the way we're seeing or we work and we see some organizations work as well.
It's basically they let the developer make those decisions.
We depend pretty heavily on feature facts.
So we say develop, go for it, make other product decisions.
Everything is feature flagged. Why?
Because we need to be able to merge it quickly as otherwise there's
merge conflicts, a really rapid rate just because of the velocity.
And then we let the the people
who care about UX and nuances of the feature, even QA,
they can open follow up pull requests to clean it up.
So yes, we must definitely push our developers
to make the decision and just get the feature out.
And we feel very comfortable with opening follow up request or
like a feature maybe like 3 or 4 pull requests and that's totally fine.
Hi. Do you have any rollback mechanisms
for this features built in the system, or do you just do that side?
If something got merged, it blows up production.
Do you have any automated ways to handle it?
We do depend on organizations like a CI.
To some extent, the good and the bad is the agent's model
for code base really deeply putting other coding standards
that component library and how you set up the environment.
And we will write the same way that you write.
So that means we saw organizations that write with feature flags.
The agents automatically outgroup the feature flags.
Organizations don't have that practice.
We will not introduce that practice.
On a more troubling note, organizations that don't have a lot of tests,
we see the agents don't really add test because not to practice.
We're we're going to add like a toggle.
And to force it anyway.
You're welcome to unionize.
You just follow up with, you.
Know, the harness is super lean to adapt your practices.
That's what we saw that organizations prefer.
You mentioned a few times
trying to avoid like a PR fatigue on the side of engineering.
Have you found any good ways that you can use to visualize
or communicate the amount of time developers are spending on those things?
Because we find definitely as a product, starts to write more features and put more
in, the dev teams end up slowing down because they're spending all the time
reviewing things.
That's quite hard for us to prove.
I have the same challenges internally in my auntie, and that's as well.
And so a few things.
One, when we develop a system, we optimize the agent to output as few lines code.
The agent does like optimizing reuse.
And we have a bunch of ways that you can model
the coalition dependency to actually find the components.
And we used properly.
So we saw that that helps the smaller PRS and the less PR fatigue.
And the issue with PRS, if you just go to the pull request page
is they all look the same.
And so what we did internally is we now have an agent that every player is open.
It labels the risk level and the size.
So you as a developer would see like the nine quarter quests you need to view.
And you will see that like three of those are low risk small.
You will see that one is like extra large and and you basically have
an easy way to manage it yourself.
And it doesn't become as an overwhelming as automatic nine visits
like, no, no, I have like pretty super small ones, two medium, one extra large.
I'm going to put a lot of effort there. They also factor in the risk level
and how much attention effort they put into it.
So we saw that that's been one like an easy way for them to to gauge
and to for the team leads.
They now factor that in.
So when you open they see the the amount of load on each developer
that going against size and risk and make sure that they distribute the burden.
That is unfortunately all the time we have for questions.
But the mood and team are here.
They have a booth in the exhibition area, so highly recommend
you grab them for a chat at some point today.
Let's give to miss.